# **Daria Minina**

Nationality: Belarussian Homepage: <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/daria-minina">https://sites.google.com/view/daria-minina</a>

### Summary

I am a PhD Researcher at the University of Amsterdam under the supervision of Stefanie J. Huber and Cars Hommes. I received my MPhil in Economics with honors at Tinbergen Institute in 2020 and MSc in Economics with honors at the University of Amsterdam in 2018.

#### **Positions and Affiliations**

2020- PhD Researcher, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam School of Economics, Center for

Nonlinear Dynamics in Economics and Finance (CeNDEF), Roetersstraat 11, 1018 WB

Amsterdam

#### **Research Interests**

Primary: Macroeconomics, Experimental Economics.

Secondary: Household finance, Behavioral Economics, Game Theory.

## Work in Progress

Equilibrium Selection through Laboratory Experiments in a complex OLG economy

(status: experiment conducted, data analysis completed, first draft ready; slides available upon request) jointly with Cars Hommes, Isabelle Salle and Stefanie J. Huber

### The passthrough from inflation perceptions to inflation expectations

(status: first draft ready; slides upon request) jointly Stefanie J. Huber and Tobias Schmidt

## **Education in Economics**

2018 – 2020 Tinbergen Institute, Amsterdam

MPhil. in Economics (with honors)

Thesis Title: "Equilibrium Selection through Laboratory Experiments in a complex

OLG economy'

Advisors: Stefanie Huber, Cars Hommes

2018 University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam

Master of Sciences (MSc) in Economics (with honors) Specialization in Behavioral Economics and Game Theory

2015 Belarussian State University, Minsk

Master of Sciences (MSc) in Economics (with honors) Specialization in Mathematical methods in Economics

2009-2014 Belarussian State University, Minsk

Bachelor degree in Economics (with honors)

### Other Training and Courses

June 14 – 2021 **Online** 

Experimental Finance Virtual Summer School, University of Bonn

April 19 – 23 2021	Online PhD course on Subjective Beliefs in Macroeconomics and Household Finance
June 20- July 1 2016	Institute for capacity development, IMF, Washington DC Certificate of completion (Course "Using DSGE-models for policy analysis")
December 4-18 2015	Joint Vienna Institute, IMF, Vienna Certificate of completion (Course "Monetary Policy Analysis")
March 2-13 2015	Joint Vienna Institute, IMF, Vienna Certificate of completion (Course "Macroeconomic Forecasting")
2013-2014  Online courses October 2016	BEROC, Minsk Certificate of completion (Postgraduate School in Economics)
	International Monetary Fund Verified certificate of completion ("Financial Programming and Policies II")
December 2015	Verified certificate of completion ("Macroeconomic forecasting")
November 2014	Verified certificate of completion ("Debt Sustainability Analysis")
July 2014	Verified certificate of completion ("Financial Programming and Policies")

# **Academic References**

Professor Cars Hommes University of Amsterdam Roetersstraat 11, 1001 NJ Amsterdam, Netherlands + 31205254246	Assistant Professor Stefanie Huber University of Amsterdam Roetersstraat 11, 1001 NJ Amsterdam, Netherlands	Professor Joep Sonnemans University of Amsterdam Roetersstraat 11, 1001 NJ Amsterdam, Netherlands +31205254249
C.H.Hommes@uva.nl	s.j.huber@uva.nl	J.H.Sonnemans@uva.nl

# **Professional and Teaching References**

Mikhail Pranovich	Dhr Eugène Hoogstad	Kristina Manysheva
International Monetary Fund	Univeristy of Amsterdam	Northwestern Univeristy
700 19th Street,	Plantage Muidergracht 12	Evanston, Illinois,
Washington DC, USA	1001 NL Amsterdam, Netherlands	United States
MPranovich@imf.org	E.E.Hoogstad@uva.nl	cmanysheva@gmail.com

# **Professional and Academic Experience**

10/2017 – 06/2018	Centre for Blended Learning, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam Student Assistant (designed educational modules for the online platform)
11/2016 – 08/2017	Embassy of the United Kingdom in Belarus, Minsk Economic Diplomacy Assistant
06/2015 – 10/2016	Ministry of Economy of Belarus, Minsk Senior economist (full-time)
07/2014 – 16/2015	Ministry of Economy of Belarus, Minsk Leading economist (full-time)
09/2013 – 07/2014	Research Institute of the Ministry of Economy of Belarus, Minsk

Junior Research Fellow (Internship)

07/2007 - 04/2014 BPS-Sberbank, Minsk

**Economist** 

### **Teaching Experience in Economics**

University of Amsterdam

2020 - Teaching assistant for *Multivariable Calculus* (Undergraduate Course, Instructor:

Florian Wagener)

Teaching assistant for Mathematical Economics II (Undergraduate Course,

Instructor: Jan Tuinstra)

**Tinbergen Institute, Amsterdam** 

2020-2022 Teaching assistant for Behavioral Macro and Complexity Summer School

(Graduate level, Instructor: Cars Hommes)

Tinbergen Institute, Amsterdam

2020 Teaching assistant for Econometrics II

(MPhil Course, Instructors: Bas van der Klaauw, Hans Bloemen)

2016-2017 Belarusian State University, Minsk

Teaching assistant for Corporate Finance

(Undergraduate Course)

# Awards, Scholarships, and Certificates

Scholarships Full scholarship, Tinbergen Institute scholarship program for Research Master

students

Amsterdam Merit Scholarship, University of Amsterdam

### **Conferences and Seminar Presentations**

2022	4 <sup>th</sup> Behavioral Macroeconomics Workshop (hybrid: online and in Bamberg, Germany)
2022	12th annual meeting of the Society for Experimental Finance (Bonn, Germany)
2022	12th Workshop on Theoretical and Experimental Macroeconomics (Berlin, Germany)
2022	49th OeNB Economic Conference and 35th SUERF Colloquium (Vienna, Austria)
2021	27th International Conference on Computing in Economics and Finance (online)
2019	2018 Conference of Young Researchers in Economics and Finance (Minsk, Belarus)

### **Computer Skills**

Matlab, R, Stata, Python, Eviews, Otree, Z-tree

## Languages

Languages Russian (native), English (fluent), German (intermediate), Dutch (intermediate)